[Music]
the stoa
is a digital campfire where we cohere in
dialogue
about what matters most at the knife's
edge of what's happening now
to the stoa i am peter limberg the
steward of the stoa
estoa is a place for us to cohere and
dialogue about what matters most
at the nice edge of this moment and
today
uh we have a very special guest tashin
fogelman tashin is one of the monastics
at the
monastic academy um and we've had other
guests from the monastic academy via
yazna who's in the
room right now who her name is her
dharma name is satian
by the way we have daniel thorsen and
then soryu himself uh
the owl came on the stowa and uh and
tashan
also writes an excellent blog on
meditation monasteries productivity
strategy and more
and today's talk is about one of the
blog posts that he had called the art of
alliances
so that being said tasha is going to
share his thoughts we can do a
powerpoint presentation and then we'll
do either
q a or um some kind of uh
uh activity uh if it's a q a format uh
attachment how it usually works is
people write their questions in the chat
box and then i call on them but we can
mix it up if you so choose
so that being said i will
allow everyone to unmute themselves and
if you can keep yourself
on mute and then i'll take you in
passion
great nice to see everybody uh
uh having difficulty hearing me can
people hear me okay
okay great looks like one person can't
but
most people can
so before i get started if you wouldn't
mind
could you just pop in the chat if you
feel so called it's not
required but could you just pop like why
you came or what you're hoping to get
out of this or
what interested you about the
description or anything like that don't
have to but would love to just hear from
a few people in the chat
kind of what brought you here
hmm
awesome some great descriptions here so
people came for a lot of different
reasons
uh people are interested in alliances
relationships
uh curious about how alliances relate to
wisdom
competition other people not sure what's
going on but just curious
so good to get a feel for where
everyone's at
so let me turn this on one second
where's everyone see this okay
great okay
okay great uh oh now you can't see it
one second
uh sorry i'm not sure how to uh
[Music]
here i'll just hide that that'll have to
be good for now i'm
having difficulty doing the full screen
but
um everyone see that okay
okay great so um this talk is based off
of
a blog post that i wrote last year i'm
assuming that
some of you will have read it and some
of you won't so i'll be covering some of
the same ideas but hopefully
giving it a little bit of an update and
a spin for everyone here
just a little bit about myself i'm
tushin as uh peter said and
i'm currently at our monastery
in the bay area we have three locations
now we started in
vermont and we have a location in the
bay area in berkeley where i'm at and
station and cullen are at willow in
toronto in the toronto area
so a lot of the work that
i'm doing with alliances is based off
what we're doing
at maple at the monastic academy i'm
trying to help our monasteries to
flourish and grow
and we have this kind of uh broad
world-saving project that needs to grow
uh from
one to two to three to ultimately we
hope to have 500 monasteries
there's this big ambitious world-saving
project and i'm imagining uh that people
here also have
some kind of ambition or they want to
save the world in some capacity they
have something
to offer that they want to offer to the
world and
see realize and so um
a lot of what i'm talking about with
alliances
can be uh sort of seen from
the light of this perspective that we
want to save the world or we have
something that we need to realize some
goal some project
that we want to bring about a lot of
this might be
seen as sort of uh
there's sort of an overlap with what you
might call like traditional
networking advice or something like that
but for me this is really coming from
a perspective of i want to help save the
world i want to
realize a better world for ourselves for
all humans
and even for all life on earth and so
a lot of these things will make sense if
you're in that context and then
you know i've heard from some people
sometimes like oh this seems kind of
creepy or weird
the way that you're looking at this and
i think it doesn't make so much sense if
you don't have
these ambitions or you don't want to
save the world you're not
aiming in that direction if you just
kind of want to run your own company or
something like that
maybe it won't make as much sense but if
you have these big ambitions or you
really want to
uh have a benefit on the world then a
lot of the strategies that i'll be
talking about today will kind of make
more sense
um at the monastery we talk about this
in terms of
trustworthy leaders and i have a
separate post about this uh
that you can read but we say that we a
trustworthy leader is someone who has
these three skills
of wisdom love and power and that those
are mutually reinforcing
so the wisdom comes from the meditation
component from contemplative practice
the love comes from seeing others
perspectives caring about others
benefiting them and the power is what
we're talking about today
in terms of strategy how do you really
have an impact how do you
really help people uh what do you
actually do to make that
happen so if you have these ambitions if
you're
sort of seeking power to put it bluntly
then alliances are going to make sense
if you have love and you see clearly
that other people are suffering and
there are real problems in the world
then this is going to make sense if you
have wisdom
if you see reality clearly you'll see
that power has enormous uh
effect in the world and that it's worth
acquiring power so
from these angles it makes sense to
cultivate power it makes sense to have
strategy it makes sense to
cultivate alliances if you're not coming
from that angle it may not be
so helpful
a lot of my thinking about these topics
comes from studying the work of sama
borya who's a friend of mine and i'm
pretty sure he participates in the stoa
regularly is that right peter
yeah so um this is a quote that
from his work green founder theory that
really
captivated me for a few reasons it says
power
can be used to accomplish a very broad
range of goals
as such many kinds of actors will aim to
acquire power
in the pursuit of their goals the more
effective they are
and the better their understanding of
reality is the likelier
they are to seek power this is a very
fascinating claim he says
the more you understand reality the more
you're going to want power
and we at the monastery are seeking to
cultivate
this direct understanding of reality
that's what you could define wisdom as
do you clearly see what's actually
happening away from human perspectives
away from traditional stories about
looking at things can you see things
clearly directly do you understand
reality
and if you understand that reality then
naturally you'll want power and so that
sort of leads to this
wisdom to power arrow samo himself not
coming from
a contemplative background stumbled on
this he says if you understand reality
you're going to want power so if
if that's you if you are seeking power
if you have these ambitions if you have
the compassion to kind of
save the world then that's why uh
alliances might be helpful and
i hope that they'll benefit you and uh
moving forward with these
different projects as far as i can tell
i don't really understand everything in
the world i'm not omniscient but
there are real problems that we're
facing there's there are
clear crises that we're facing
collectively as a species and on the
planet
and my goal bluntly speaking is to save
the world
that's what i'm trying to do it's sort
of uh
not kosher in some circles to say that
it's like oh are you naive or
silly or something but as far as i can
tell the world
needs saving and so that's why it makes
sense to have these
different world-saving projects like the
monastery like things that other people
are doing
none of these are sufficient we're going
to need a lot of different
perspectives and angles and skills and
practices
but i think that these different things
are necessary
and uh are what's needed to actually
save the world
and a big part of that is that you can't
really save the world by yourself
uh i would have done it already if i
could you would have probably done it
already if you could no one
single-handedly can save the world
alone it's actually something that needs
to be done together
and that's where alliances start to make
sense
in alliance you work closely with one
two
three other people or organizations many
people even
many organizations but you kind of have
a clear sense of
who you're working with what the
different skills and strengths and
weaknesses are of people
and you try to go in that direction
you're trying to realize something
bigger and better
than you could realize on your own
it's another quote from samo he's in
general he's interested in
competitive uh things like uh money or
power politics things like this
um so and he says interestingly that the
best way to win
adversarial encounters is to focus
energy on building out
cooperative relationships so even in the
context of adversarial competitive
domains
the best strategy is to cooperate build
out cooperative relationships
in the long run acquiring power and
empowering others are mutually
reinforcing
rather than mutually exclusive so if you
get power and you share it with others
that's going to bring you more power in
the future than if you had just kept
that power
for yourself
this is also a very different way of
looking things than
you know you may have been used to
people often think of power as sort of
zero sum you know i'm gonna get power
and you don't have it they have power
and i don't
but this is a way of looking at power
that we want to cooperate
we want the most people to have the most
power for the most good
so in that context he starts talking
about alliances he makes a distinction
between a narrow and a broad alliance
so most alliances are narrow he says two
players can cooperate in one domain
while battling in a different domain i
call this a narrow alliance
so an example of this might be say
a politician walks into a convenience
store
temporarily they have an alliance the
cashier
the store owners and the politician they
they all want the politician to purchase
like peanuts or something
uh get some kind of snack at the grocery
store or the convenience store
but as soon as that transaction is done
their relationship
is over they may have totally different
politics they may want to see a
different
world realize they may even hate each
other but they all want the politician
to
purchase a snack at the convenience
store
this is sort of an extreme example but a
lot of things are like this if you have
a relationship with a co-worker for
example uh
that might very well be a narrow
alliance where you work together
in the context of uh you know the work
that you're working on together
but then at the end of the day you two
aren't necessarily friends or aren't
very close
you don't have these long-term existing
relationships that
you cooperate no matter what in whatever
context you're in
and that's what abroad alliances says
when two players are coordinating
to achieve most of their goals and no
longer contest one each other
one another i call it a broad alliance
so a good example of this would be uh
station and i we're
on the same team uh she's at willow i'm
here at oak sometimes i'm at medieval
there are different contexts that we
work together but we're always on
each other's team we're trying to help
each other in different ways
there's a lot of different ways that we
help each other we're always trying to
stay
apprised of what each other are doing
and we work well together and are trying
to
realize something bigger and better than
just what we would do
alone he also says something very
interesting to me here he says that
narrow alliances are the default between
most players and an empire that's
samo's technical vocabulary but he says
broad alliances are unusual
and for me this was just reading that
sentence was
revelatory because i realized that in
the monastery in the monastic setting
broad alliances are actually normal it's
normal to have a broad alliance with
someone
all the time your roles are changing
people come and go from the monastery
even when they're in the monastery
they're changing locations or roles
all of the times the circumstances are
changing and yet
you have these continued relationships
where you're really trying to support
each other you trust each other
you see that the other person is a good
person trying to bring about good things
in the world
and you want to help them no matter what
so you know again station and i have
been in many different kinds of
contexts and relationships with each
other but we're always trying to help
each other and that's
that's actually normal i could talk
about anyone in the monastic training
that i've done and
the default would be for me that i've
have a broad alliance
but in most domains in most settings
narrow alliances are the norm
where you just have these like short
term or sort of narrow
focused alliances and what we're talking
about here
is broad alliances we want to cultivate
notice
build deepen strengthen these
broad alliances that's what we're
talking about today
so there's a few different ways to look
at power and the basic
distinction that i would say is worth
looking at is
the distinction between networks and
hierarchies
in social science this is sort of the
equivalent of
uh particle and wave distinction
a lot of times people make these into
kind of a binary where like
oh i don't like hierarchical power i
want these like networks or like
anarchical power
things like this um but at least as far
as i can tell most social structures
are a mixture of both there are
you can describe power and social
structures
either in a networked view or
hierarchies view just in the same way
that
subatomic particles can be seen as
particles or waves
and then the way that you look at them
changes you come to different
results based on that
so it's worth looking at alliances both
from the perspective of networks
and from the perspective of hierarchies
i'll start with networks because i think
it's a little bit easier to understand
uh the applications here so
uh this is a diagram that i made with an
ally of men very close
ally and we basically made a map of our
different networks you know i don't have
the names in here
but i'm the dot at the bottom and he's
the dot at the top
and we sort of mapped out the different
people that we're connected to that we
have
alliances with and what their uh
who they are and how they're connected
so uh the big
gray dots are different organizations
um and then the little gray dots are
different people that we knew and then
again the black dots
are my ally and me so in some cases
he and i had mutual connections where we
were both connected to
uh particular people but in some cases
he was connected to people that i wasn't
and i was connected to people
that he wasn't connected to and so then
the question became
what is going on here um are there any
connections that would be
worth making that aren't currently
connected you know maybe this person on
the far right would really benefit
from knowing this person on the far
bottom left they're they're both working
on similar things or they have something
that they
could support each other in and you can
look at it in this networked view where
rather than you know seeing things in
terms of specific organizations you can
see
lots of different nodes and the
connections between the nodes and see if
there's anything
that's kind of inviting itself to arise
is there anything that could emerge from
what's present here
that's greater than what's already
present
from this perspective i think about it
in terms of serving the network
so of course i care about the monastery
and our local goals
uh i care about the network that i'm in
of multiple monasteries seeing that
succeed seeing that flourish
i have those aims but i also care about
the overall network
i also care about other people even if
they're not in the project
that i'm in they i want to see them
benefited
um so sometimes uh there are non-obvious
connections that
are just waiting to happen that i can
help happen and typically of course you
want to make sure that both people are
uh interested in this uh
connection you want to get sort of
what's known as a double opt-in
introduction
you talk to one person and say hey
there's this other person they're like
this would you like to
meet them and then you talk to the other
person hey there's this person would you
like to meet them and if they're both
interested in meeting each other then
you make the introduction
um but in any case that kind of
introduction can really help someone say
one person needs this really obscure
like programming skill and then
someone else has that and is looking for
a job then that can
you can connect them together and
something will happen that wasn't
predicted
it doesn't necessarily directly benefit
you but the network as a whole
is stronger the the
everyone is benefited when there are
these stronger connections
so that's the networked view of power
the other one is hierarchies
and most people have this kind of a view
of a hierarchy where there's like a ceo
a vice president and multiple teams of
like individual contributors for example
in other words an org chart an
organization chart
that's a really valid way to look at
hierarchies
those are relevant to know the official
or chart
of an organization but it's sort of a
limited view
often in social structures and power the
way that things are
explicitly presented is not the full
reality there's sort of implicit uh
information there that may not be
explicit or made verbal
is like shared verbal knowledge between
people there are sort of these
different connections that people have
that might be like back channels or like
secret alliances or maybe two people
like secretly hate each other or
things like this um so this is a drawing
from tom crichlow
uh who recently wrote a great post about
navigating power and he's got this like
much more
realistic map uh and the details don't
matter so much as like
uh actually there's a lot more people
and there's these secret
you know hidden relationships and he's
sort of working he's coming
from the context of being an outside
consultant hired to work with a company
and so he's trying to make his own
internal personal map
of what's going on in the organization
so even though they've got their
official
uh org chart he's trying to work out who
really has power
you know who's secretly you know
headlined here
uh even though they still have
officially recognized power they're not
actually in power things like this
this happens all the time and so uh it's
useful to know that the
explicit org chart of an organization is
not necessarily the real
power structure at least in terms of you
know whatever goals you may have
this is true for organizations that
you're in but also working with
other organizations um you know so i
i think about these hierarchies for my
own organization
we have multiple locations and so each
of those has a hierarchy and then
there's a hierarchy of the overall
organizations
and i've got basically a power map in my
head
of how those are related but then i also
make these maps
in my head for for other organizations
that i'm working with say
peter invites me to the stoa you know
that's like a separate organization that
i'm not part of but
he wants me to be part of it that's the
kind of thing where it might be useful
for me to
make a map either in my head or
explicitly
of what the power structures are there
and so that's the context that i
invented borea mapping in
uh this is kind of combining samo's
empire theory with
simon wordley's worldly mapping uh
basically making a visual representation
of hierarchies and that's
something you can read more about after
this uh talk
but the idea is that there are these
different power classes
uh high mid low and then also out so in
the example of the stoa i would be
out with respect to the stoa because i'm
not in the organization officially but
i'm still connected to it
and then there's uh live and dead
players
people who are they're not literally
alive or dead
but this is what i call vitality so
some people are just following an
existing script and some people are
doing things
that are novel and in a totally new way
and that's uh
live or dead so in this case the
engineer who technically has
low power is a live player who's doing
things
in a new way that hasn't been done
before whereas the ceo and the hr
department
are you know doing the normal day-to-day
things that they've always done for the
last decade
even though the engineer is doing
something totally new and that's
actually a form of power in itself
even if you're low in the official
hierarchy you can have
uh a lot of power in terms of the skills
that you have or how you're doing things
and then there's actually a third axis
here the uh you can see different colors
so uh the green is like who you are
aligned
allied with who you're working with who
you have a good relationship with yellow
is someone that's neutral
and then the red is like an enemy you
know they may not be trying to kill you
but they might not be on your same team
with respect to the things that you're
trying to accomplish and so you want to
know that
sometimes people are just going to be
antagonistic to the things you're trying
to bring about
and rather than being blind to that like
oh you know we're all in this together
uh you want to be aware if someone's
actively working against you or is just
kind of
biased against it so that you can take
that into account and
uh act differently
so this is sort of a simplistic one but
here's another example of a boream app
that's more complicated
probably more realistic as well that's
based off of
a chapter in simon's book uh called the
scenario he has this really lovely
uh like exercise in his book that you're
supposed to use
to make a worldly map to see if you
understand it and
how also how what decisions you would be
made you would make based off of the
information that he gives you
um but it's also a good chance to map
uh social structures using this empire
theory
or borea mapping and so i made a map of
that and this is more realistic because
typically organizations have you know on
the order of like
15 20 people or more or something like
that and you'll see in this case
some of these are like teams a digital
team for example
um sales team and so on and those can be
treated as whole entities or in samos
language empires
for themselves so my suggestion is
uh basically if you're working with a
hierarchical power structure
either your own organization or someone
else's of course you want to be aware of
the official sanctioned org charts
but you also want to have your own
mental understanding of
the power dynamics in that organization
again whether it's your own or someone
else's
that there are these different power
dynamics and you want to have a solid
understanding of that and making your
own kind of map can be helpful for that
this is just the way that i make these
maps but
you can make your own drawing i mean uh
we saw uh
tom's drawing back here this is how he
draws them out it doesn't really matter
how you draw them out you don't even
need to draw them out the idea is you
just you want to have your own
understanding of the power dynamics
especially because these are constantly
changing and certainly they're not
always reflective of the officially
sanctioned
power statements about power
a lot of the things that people tend to
do when they realize this is make a swot
diagram
and there's this really lovely chapter
in simon's book where he makes fun of
this
he talks about the example of the
mysticallys in
what's now known as kinglionitis and the
300 spartans
uh he's making the point that where you
choose a battle really matters and so
they
they had this battle in the hot gates uh
where the like
300 or 4 000 greeks could fight against
say
200 000 persians and because they picked
that location to fight
it they had much higher success than
they would have
otherwise and that's because simon's
claiming they had an actual map
of the landscape um and so he's like
what if
uh you know the mysticallys had said uh
no worries everyone i made a swat
diagram uh
instead of a map uh we're gonna be great
these are our strengths these are
weaknesses now let's do battle
it's kind of silly and this is the view
that i'd always had of swat diagrams
they never really made sense to me why
you would make them uh it's like okay
people have strengths and weaknesses
what are these opportunities what are
these threats
uh but i would say that in the context
of something like your own
understanding of the landscape of power
whether it's a boream app or something
else
then given that assuming you have that
as a prerequisite
then a swot diagram starts to make a lot
of sense because you do have an actually
good map
of the social reality so if you
juxtapose this sort of thing or this
sort of thing
or this sort of thing with a swot
diagram
then it starts to make sense so this is
an example
fake swot diagram that i made i actually
like to use different terms for the last
two because they sort of make more sense
to me i talk about them in terms of
objectives and traps
so people have different strengths and
weaknesses and you want to know
what their strengths and weaknesses are
but you also want to know what their
goals are or their objectives
so this person joe who's in your
organization as a fundraiser he has his
own goals he wants to
in this case increase his money and get
a promotion
he wants to increase his earnings as a
fundraiser and make a promotion
so he has his own personal goals that
may or may not be related to the goals
of the larger organization you want to
know that
and then you have traps you are
understand that you yourself
also have strengths and weaknesses and
so you have this inter-personal
interrelational
uh traps thing where it's like okay
given what i know about myself
and given what i know about other people
uh
what are the possible traps that we
could fall into what are the things that
we could do that would be
problematic um so in this case i was
like
well because he's sort of aloof and
impulsive
he might not seek feedback when he needs
it and he might
resign if he feels isolated for long
periods of time
so that's kind of uh you know an extreme
example that i just made up but
you know when we have these
relationships with people there are
traps that we can fall into
where you know you have your weaknesses
and they have their weaknesses and that
those can combine
in to create friction and you want to
anticipate that
rather than you know just stumbling into
it
unknowingly um so the point here is if
you have
a landscape of power that you've sort of
drawn out that you've mapped out
then it makes more sense to have a swot
diagram where you
kind of take stock of different people's
strengths and weaknesses
also their goals and any traps that you
might fall into
and this is actually a similar point
that simon makes there's
something like 18 chapters later in his
book he's like
oh let's make a swat diagram and he says
swat isn't that the curse of simplistic
management
yes but it also has its uses
particularly if we understand the
landscape
if we have a map in other words the
problem with swot isn't that it's
useless but instead that we
apply it to landscapes we don't
understand so in the same way
if we have a map of social reality where
we understand the different power
dynamics
and that is somewhat accurate not just
giving in to the official org chart but
sort of a more nuanced understanding
then it makes sense to have a swap
diagram
and you can actually make these not only
for individual people but also
teams or organizations as a whole so
like
something you really need to be aware of
is everyone
both individuals and teams and
organizations they all have strengths
and weaknesses
i personally have strengths and
weaknesses you personally have strengths
and weaknesses
you know the monastery has strengths and
weaknesses
maybe willow and oak are california
location and
canada locations maybe they have
different strengths and weaknesses
maybe the stoa has different strengths
and weaknesses we all have different
goals
and we have different traps that we can
fall into interrelationally so you can
kind of
map this out at any scope of attention
that you want
i could make a map just of our
california location or
of our national organization as a whole
i could make a map of the stoa
i could make a map of any organization
google facebook whatever
and you can do that at any scale and all
of those are going to have
strengths weaknesses objectives or goals
and
traps that you could fall into in
relation
with those different scales
so one of the really nice things about
alliances is that you can have
uh very blunt conversations whenever i
talk to my allies
we just have these very frank
conversations that aren't always
uh necessarily like socially sanctioned
if you just have
like chat over coffee and you know for
example
the basic question is what do you need
so
typically my allies will really need
something there's something they're
bottlenecked on
and i want to know what that is in case
i'm suddenly able to
provide that to them that i might not be
able to often i'm not but if i know
about it then that's the first
step to being able to realize that i
want to have this kind of situational
awareness of
what they're doing what's going well
what's not going well what kind of
challenges are they facing
what are they learning and what do they
need
and if i know all of those things then i
might be able to help
and similarly i want other people to
know what's going on with me and
my goals and my or you know what's going
on with our organization
and have that situational awareness into
what i'm doing so that if they suddenly
have the conditions
to help me then they will help me
you know so for our organization this is
this is a diagram that i made of what i
think we need
monasteries have the opportunity to
create these trustworthy leaders
these trustworthy communities culture
economy and
ultimately a trustworthy humanity but
all of that is only possible if we have
money
land and people and specifically uh
right now we're doing pretty well on
people we have
a lot of interest we're doing okay on
land
we're hoping to move in california to a
new location
but the main thing that we seem to be
bottlenecked on both at our individual
locations and also as our organization
as whole is money
and so with my allies i can just frankly
say look we're trying to raise this much
money
for these reasons uh do you know anyone
that would help and maybe they do
and maybe they don't but at least i can
talk to them very frankly about it and
you know often they're able to connect
me with people who might want to give us
money or might want to give us land or
might know someone who wants to join the
monastery or something like that and if
i can just speak
bluntly about that with them then it's
more likely that it's gonna
happen and they can speak similarly
bluntly with me you know they can say
oh we're having this problem in our
engineering team and we're switching to
this new technology and i don't really
understand
it but we need more people that
understand this and
then i might meet someone who knows
about that and is actually looking for a
job
and i can connect them and so there's no
guarantee that you're gonna
get what you need but if if having an
alliance like this or even many
alliances like this
a strong network of alliances indeed is
the conditions for
good consequences to arise for someone
someone will kind of
uh benefit from having these uh this
awareness of
who your alliances are and what they
need and what's happening for them